EDUARDO DA VEIGA BELTRAME

Graduate Student in Bioengineering at Caltech

Email: edaveiga@caltech.edu Personal website: munfred.com

EDUCATION

Graduate Student in Bioengineering Caltech Bioengineering Program

B.S. Biological Physics

Brandeis University

2014 - 2016 (transfer)

Waltham, MA

Federal University of Santa Catarina (UFSC)

2011 - 2014

♥ Florianópolis, Brazil

Electronics Technician

Federal Institute of Santa Catarina (IFSC)

2007 - 2010

♥ Florianópolis, Brazil

Combined highschool and technical program.

EXPERIENCE

Sternberg Lab - Graduate student

♀ Caltech

I work on leveraging single cell data for studying the nematode C. elegans, and integrating this data to the biological knowledge base WormBase.

Pachter Lab - Graduate student

2018 - 2019

♀ Caltech

Worked on new experimental and computational methods for single cell RNA sequencing experiments.

Ginkgo Bioworks - Intern

Feburary - August 2018

Boston, MA

During a 6 months internship I worked on data analysis and proteomics assays using mass spectrometry.

Kondev Group - Research Assistant

2015-2016

♀ Brandeis University

Investigated gene expression and bacterial transcription processes using analytic and computational models.

Katz Lab - Research Assistant

2015-2016

Prandeis University

Performed neuroscience research about memory formation using electrophysiology, molecular and behavioral techniques.

Structural Biology Lab - Research Assistant

2013-2014

♀ UFSC, Brazil

Investigated protein nitrosylation reactions using mass spectrometry and molecular dynamics.

LANGUAGES

- Portuguese, Native
- English, fluent
- Spanish, fluent (lived in Spain for 6 months)
- Mandarin, basic (studied for 18 months)

HIGHLIGHTS

Ran the <u>Brandeis 3D printing club</u> and helped create the <u>Brandeis MakerLab</u>

Created hundreds of 3D printed biomolecular models for teaching and research on the life sciences.

Co-developed the low cost, open source and 3D printable poseidon syringe pump system.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python for data analysis and machine learning
- Linux systems management
- HTML and web design
- 3D printing and 3D design

PUBLICATIONS

Quantifying the tradeoff between sequencing depth and cell number in single-cell RNA-seq. bioRxiv 2019. doi.org/10.1101/762773

A curated database reveals trends in single cell transcriptomics. bioRxiv 2019. doi.org/10.1101/742304

Modular and efficient pre-processing of single-cell RNA-seq. bioRxiv 2019. doi.org/10.1101/673285

Deletion of Stk11 and Fos in mouse BLA projection neurons alters intrinsic excitability and impairs formation of long-term aversive memory. bioRxiv 2019. doi.org/10.1101/787325

Principles of open source bioinstrumentation applied to the poseidon syringe pump system. Scientific Reports, 2019. doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-48815-9

3D printing of biomolecular models for research and pedagogy. JoVE, 2017. doi.org/10.3791/55427